A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Task Force on Academic Health Centers, SG 3, Series 4 FA1461
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Task Force on Academic Health Centers, SG 3, Series 4
1993-2000
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA1461
3.8 Cubic Feet 10 letter-size document boxes.
Arrangement
Records remain in original order, as received.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund records were donated to RAC in 1985. The initial transfer of archival records to RAC began in 1986, and transfers continue on a regular basis. This series was transferred to RAC as accession 2007:077.
Scope and Contents
This series documents the Commonwealth Fund Task Force on Academic Health Centers. The majority of the material is grant administration files pertaining to the Task Force. These records often include documentation of: proposals, administration and budget, grant products, related correspondence and background material. A limited selection of Task Force meeting files is also included.
- Georgetown University - Hadley - Preserving the Role of Academic Health Centers (94-56) - Readings (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Georgetown University - Hadley - Preserving the Role of Academic Health Centers (94-56) - Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Georgetown University - Hadley - Preserving the Role of Academic Health Centers (94-56) - Grant Products, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Georgetown University - Hadley - Preserving the Role of Academic Health Centers (94-56), 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Georgetown University - Hadley - Preserving the Role of Academic Health Centers (94-56) - Administration, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Harvard Medical School - Blumenthal - Case Studies in Academic Health (94-57), 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Harvard Medical School - Blumenthal - Case Studies in Academic Health (94-57), 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Harvard Medical School - Blumenthal - Case Studies in Academic Health (94-57) - Readings (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Harvard Medical School - Blumenthal - Case Studies in Academic Health (94-57) - Administration and Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Harvard Medical School - Blumenthal - Case Studies in Academic Health (94-57) - Grant Products, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Case Studies: Academic Health Centers in Tennesseee (95735), 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Administration of Task Force on Academic Health Centers (96013) - Andrulis Subcontract, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Administration of Task Force on Academic Health Centers (96013) - Administration and Budget, 1995-2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Administration of Task Force on Academic Health Centers (96013) - Grant Products, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Administration of Task Force on Academic Health Centers (96013) - Missions Paper (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Program Direction (96958) - Academic Health Centers Board Write-Up, 1996 July (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Program Direction (96958) - Overview (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Program Direction (96958) - Academic Health Centers Mailing List (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Program Direction (96958) - Proposal Development, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Program Direction (96958) - Task Force Forum (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Program Direction (96958) - Faculty Survey, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Program Direction (96958) - Administration and Budget, 1997-2000 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Massachusetts General Hospital - Blumenthal - Program Direction (96958) - Grant Products (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Academic Health Centers Task Force Meeting, 1996 April 17 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Academic Health Centers Task Force Meeting - Current Status and Future Prospects, 1996 November 21 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Georgetown University - Reuter - The Impact of Managed Care and Public Policy Changes on Academic Health Centers (95450) - Administration, Correspondence, Background (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Georgetown University - Reuter - The Impact of Managed Care and Public Policy Changes on Academic Health Centers (95450) - Financing of Academic Health Centers' Chartbook (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Georgetown University - Reuter - The Impact of Managed Care and Public Policy Changes on Academic Health Centers (95450) - Grant Products (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Association of Academic Health Centers - Osterweis (20000641) (Box 5, Folder 29)
- American Medical Association - Barzansky - The Impact of Managed Care on Medical Education (96347), 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Association of Academic Health Centers - Bulger (970710) (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Association of American Medical Colleges - Korn - National Clinical Research Summit (980732), 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education - Leach (20000036) (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Association for Health Services Research - Valentine (990421) (Box 5, Folder 34)
- DataStat - Magilavy - Survey of MD Residents on the Impact of Changes in the Health Care Market on MD Training (970591) - RFP, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 35)
- DataStat - Magilavy - Survey of MD Residents on the Impact of Changes in the Health Care Market on MD Training (970591), 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- DataStat - Magilavy - Survey of MD Residents on the Impact of Changes in the Health Care Market on MD Training (970591) - Proposal Development (Box 6, Folder 37)
- Lewin Group - Dobson - The Social Missions of Academic Health Centers: A Cost Analysis (98017) - Proposal Development and Administration, 1997-2001 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Lewin Group - Dobson - The Social Missions of Academic Health Centers: A Cost Analysis (98017) - Correspondence and Background (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Lewin Group - Dobson - The Social Missions of Academic Health Centers: A Cost Analysis (98017) - Grant Products, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Lewin Group - Dobson - Analysis of Graduate Medical Education Costs (970440 PDF), 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Lewin Group (94-56) - Community Hospitals and Academic Health Centers, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Association of American Medical Colleges - Griner - Improving Information on the Missions of Academic Health Centers (96176) - Administration, 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Association of American Medical Colleges - Griner - Improving Information on the Missions of Academic Health Centers (96176) - Academic Health Centers - Data System (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Association of American Medical Colleges - Griner - Improving Information on the Missions of Academic Health Centers (96176) - Grant Products (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Association of American Medical Colleges - Griner - Improving Information on Ability of Academic Health Centers to Achieve their Missions (Phase II) (96160) - Proposal Development, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 46)
- Association of American Medical Colleges - Griner - Improving Information on Ability of Academic Health Centers to Achieve their Missions (Phase II) (96160) - Administration and Correspondence, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 47)
- Association of American Medical Colleges Factsheets (Box 8, Folder 48)
- Association of American Medical Colleges - Griner - Improving Information on Ability of Academic Health Centers to Achieve their Missions (Phase II) (96160) - Grant Products (Box 8, Folder 49-50)
- Academic Health Centers Policy Recommendations Report, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 51)
- Academic Health Centers Policy Recommendations Report, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 52)
- Lynn Lewis (Box 9, Folder 53)
- Academic Health Centers Policy Report - Task Force Member Comments, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 54)
- Prologue - Executive Summary, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 55)
- Business Communications, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 56)
- Brazda Breakfast, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 57)
- University of Virginia Health Policy Center - Detmer (980274) - Academic Health Center Orientation for New University Presidents, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 58)
- Johns Hopkins University - Anderson - Estimating the Impact of Foreign Medical Graduate Students on Medicare Spending (95016), 1995 (Box 9, Folder 59)
- Institute of Medicine - Herdman - National Graduate Medical Education Trust Fund (970356), 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 60)
- International Center for Health Outcomes and Innovation Research, Columbia University - Rettig - The Role of Academic Health Centers in Diffusion of Medical Technology (990539), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 61)
- Harvard Pilgrim Health Center - Moore (PDF 980666) (Box 10, Folder 62)
- Health Research, Inc. (971028) - SUNY-Albany - Salsberg - State Meeting, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 63)
- Health Policy Alternatives, HASH Report on Political Context, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 64)
- Harvard University - Epstein (970622), 1997 (Box 10, Folder 65)
- Harvard Medical School - Kleinman - Publication of Daedalus Issue (990113), 1998 (Box 10, Folder 66)